NAZAR ABDUL FATTAH

NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR AND WEB DEVELOPER

Passionate web developer with 2 years of experience as a freelancer and employee, working with startups and government projects. Currently studying Computer Engineering at Samarinda State Polytechnic. I have experience in building small to medium-scale applications and am now expanding my skills in artificial intelligence, as well as more advanced backend, frontend, and DevOps implementations.

COMPETENCIES

Networking, Routing, and PHP, Codelgniter, and Laravel Apache, and Nginx

Switching Javascript, Express.js, Vue.js, and MySQL, Firebase, and MongoDB

Network Security NestJS Git, SEO, and Redis

Google Cloud Tailwind, Quasar, and SCSS Github Actions, and Jenkins

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STIMIK Widya Cipta Dharma

Network Technical Support

January 2020 - March 2020

Internship as Network Technical Support at STMIK Widya Cipta Dharma, I maintained PCs and network interfaces in the lab, managed the computer network, and handled troubleshooting to ensure smooth and efficient system operations.

Desa Sumber Sari

Fullstack Web Developer

January 2023 - February 2023

I created a website for the village of Sumber Sari as part of a collaboration project between the village and Politeknik Negeri Samarinda. The website featured sections for news, events, a gallery, complaints, and reservations.

- · Creating backend with Laravel.
- · Creating frontend with Javascript & JQuery.
- · Creating database.
- Deploy application.

RT 08 Sempaja Utara [SIRT]

March 2023 - June 2023

June 2023 - July 2023

Fullstack Web Developer

I created a platform called SIRT in collaboration with Politeknik Negeri Samarinda and local neighborhood associations. It managed population data, scheduled meetings, drafted letters, and validated emails.

- · Creating backend with Laravel.
- · Creating frontend with Javascript & JQuery.
- Integrating to SMTP Mailtrap
- · Creating and Design database.
- Deploy application.

Pemerintah Provinsi Kalimantan Timur [SIBAKWAN]

interior Towns Remindred Time [SIDARWAN]

Fullstack Web Developer

I developed SIBAKWAN, a platform by the East Kalimantan government to track animal diseases with geolocation. I optimized the site, added geolocation, improved the frontend.

- Updating feature backend with Laravel.
- Updating frontend with Javascript & JQuery.
- Remoting with Git and SFTP.

PT. Sintesa Persada Teknologi [Medisin]

Fullstack Web Developer

June 2023 - August 2024

I developed an application called Medisin from PT. Sintesa Persada Teknologi, a hospital service platform serving hospitals in Indonesia. I added features like patient letters, cost recording, visit tracking, and diagnosis documentation.

- Update and Create feature backend with Laravel and Codelgniter.
- Updating frontend with Vue.js.
- · Remoting with Git and SFTP.

PT Insani Bara Perkasa [SmartSprinkler]

Fullstack Web Developer

July 2024 - December 2024

I created an application called Smart Sprinkler with Politeknik Negeri Samarinda and PT Insani Bara Perkasa to reclaim former mining lands. I developed a website to monitor and control IoT devices using MQTT and HTTP protocols.

- · Creating backend with Laravel.
- Creating frontend with Vue.js.
- Integrate Mosquitto to IoT Device and Website
- Deploy application.

ACTIVITIES

PT Agate International

Game Developer (Game Programmer)

August 2023 - December 2023

I participated as a student in the Independent Study Program at PT Agate International through the MSIB initiative. During this program, I gained knowledge and hands-on experience in game development and design, utilizing industry-standard tools and technologies.

- Learned the fundamentals of game development and design processes.
- Built games using Unity with C# programming language.
- Designed 3D models and visual elements using Blender.
- Implemented game logic, functionality, and interactive features.

Bangkit Academy 2024 By Google, GoTo, Tokopedia, Traveloka Cloud Computing

September 2024 - December 2024

I participated as a student in the Bangkit Academy 2024 program, organized by Google, GoTo, Tokopedia, and Traveloka, through the MSIB initiative. Throughout this program, I acquired essential skills in DevOps, API development, and machine learning integration using cutting-edge tools and technologies.

- Learned the fundamentals of DevOps using Google Cloud Platform.
- · Implemented machine learning models into applications and integrated them with Google Cloud.
- Gained experience in deploying and managing cloud-based solutions.
- Applied best practices for optimizing performance and scalability of applications.

EDUCATION

SMK Negeri 7 Samarinda

Computer and Network Engineering (2018 - 2021)

Politeknik Negeri Samarinda

Computer Engineering (2021 - Present)

CONTACT

Telephone 0896-2678-5887

Email nazar.af.03@gmail.com

Github NazarAF

Linkedin Nazar Abdul Fattah

Address Samarinda, East Kalimantan

CERTIFICATION

MTCNA (Mikrotik Certified Associate)

Basic networking test from Mikrotik

CCNA Routing and Switching

Routing and Switching test from Cisco

IT Essentials

System Operation and computing test from Cisco

BNSP VSGA Junior Network Administrator

Networking test from government

TOEIC (score 505,00)

English test from ETS